Sangwon Seo

(832) 839-3228 | ■ sangwon.seo@rice.edu | ★ sangwonseo.com
 in sangwon91 | ♥ SangwonSeo_ | ★ Google Scholar

Research Objectives

My research centers on Human-Robot Collaboration, Human-Centered AI, and Human Behavior Modeling. During my Ph.D., I have developed imitation learning algorithms to model human behavior and computational methods to improve both human-human and human-robot teamwork.

Education

Rice University, Houston, TX

Aug 2019 - Present

Ph.D. in Computer Science

• Thesis (Tentative): AI-Assisted Teamwork

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2013 - Feb 2015

M.S in Bioengineering

• Thesis: Performance Enhancement in Heart Rate Variability Analysis with Constrained Missing RR Interval Estimation

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2009 - Feb 2013

B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

• Thesis: Multiplexing of Bead-Based Immunoassays using a BioMEMS

Research Experience

Human-Centered AI and Robotics Group, Rice University

Aug 2020 – Present

Ph.D. Candidate (Advisor: Prof. Vaibhav Unhelkar)

- Proposed an automated task-time intervention system to improve teamwork during tasks
- Developed sample- and label-efficient imitation learning algorithms to learn a generative model of team behavior
- Developed a hierarchical imitation learning algorithm to learn the intentional behavior of experts from demonstrations
- Implemented multiple web-based teamwork simulators

Biomedical Signal and Information Lab, Seoul National University

Feb 2013 - Feb 2015

M.S Student (Advisor: Prof. Kwang Suk Park)

- Developed signal processing algorithms for daily monitoring of physiological signals
- Developed autoregressive–moving-average-based interpolation methods to fill in missing RR-interval values to enhance heart rate variability analysis

Biophotonics and Nano Engineering Lab, Seoul National University

Dec 2011 – Jun 2012

Research Intern (Advisor: Prof. Sunghoon Kwon)

• Designed and implemented biomedical microelectromechanical systems (Bio-MEMS)

Industry Experience ____

Honda Research Institute USA, San Jose, CA

May 2024 - Aug 2024

Research Intern

- Human behavior modeling and optimization for human-aware automation
- Developed mathematical models to capture changes in human propensities for interacting with other agents and learned these models from demonstrations.
- Inferred individual interaction propensities with other agents from observable states and actions using sequential Monte Carlo methods

Coreline Soft, Seoul, South Korea Associate Research Engineer Apr 2016 - Jun 2019

- Responsible for developing algorithms for AVIEW MODELER, a medical 3D printing solution
- Developed geometric modeling and processing algorithms
- Implemented a volume and surface rendering pipeline

Agency for Defense Development, Daejeon, South Korea Researcher

Mar 2015 - Mar 2016

- Developed a telemetry system for aircraft
- * My employment at the Agency for Defense Development and Coreline Soft is recognized as fulfilling the compulsory military service in South Korea.

Publications ____

Full Papers

- S. Seo and V. V. Unhelkar, "IDIL: Imitation Learning of Intent-Driven Expert Behavior", 23nd International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), 2024 (Acceptance rate 25%)
- **S. Seo**, B. Han and V. V. Unhelkar, "Automated Task-Time Interventions to Improve Teamwork using Imitation Learning", *22nd International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS)*, 2023 (Acceptance rate 23.3%)
- **S. Seo** and V. V. Unhelkar, "Semi-Supervised Imitation Learning of Team Policies from Suboptimal Demonstrations", *31st International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)*, 2022 (Acceptance rate 14.9%)
- **S. Seo**, L. R. Kennedy-Metz, M. A. Zenati, J. A. Shah, R. D. Dias and V. V. Unhelkar, "Towards an AI coach to infer team mental model alignment in healthcare", *2021 IEEE Conference on Cognitive and Computational Aspects of Situation Management (CogSIMA)*, pp. 39-44, 2021
- S. Kwon, D. Lee, J. Kim, Y. Lee, S. Kang, **S. Seo** and K. Park, "Sinabro: A smartphone-integrated opportunistic electrocardiogram monitoring system", *Sensors*, 16(3), p.361, 2016
- S. H. Hwang, **S. Seo**, H. N. Yoon, H. J. Baek, J. Cho, J. W. Choi, Y. J. Lee, D.-U. Jeong and K. Park, "Sleep period time estimation based on electrodermal activity", *IEEE journal of biomedical and health informatics (J-BHI)*, 21(1), pp.115-122, 2015
- S. Kang, S. Kwon, C. Yoo, **S. Seo**, K. Park, J. Song and Y. Lee, "Sinabro: Opportunistic and unobtrusive mobile electrocardiogram monitoring system", *15th Workshop on Mobile Computing Systems and Applications (HotMobile)*, pp. 1-6, 2014

Short Papers

- S. Seo, "AI-Assisted Human Teamwork", AAAI-24 Doctoral Consortium, 2024
- M. Khalid, S. Seo, M. A. Zenati, M. Ebnali, L. R. Kennedy-Metz, R. D. Dias, V. V. Unhelkar and E. Salas, "Opportunities and Challenges of Real-Time Measurement of Team Performance on the Cardiac Operating Room", Human Factors and Ergonomics Society (HFES) 67th International Annual Meeting, 2023
- J. Kim, S. Kwon, **S. Seo** and K. Park, "Highly wearable galvanic skin response sensor using flexible and conductive polymer foam", *36th annual international conference of the IEEE engineering in medicine and biology society (EMBC)*, pp. 6631-6634, 2014

Honors & Awards

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant

COMP 646: Deep Learning for Vision and Language (Prof. Vicente Ordóñez-Román) Spring 2023 COMP 440/557: Artificial Intelligence (Prof. Devika Subramanian) Fall 2021

Advising & Mentoring

Arnav Adhikari, Highschool Student, Houston, TXMay 2023 – PresentBing (Tim) Han, Undergraduate Student, Rice UniversityMay 2022 – PresentZhanyi Sun, Undergraduate Student, Rice UniversityJan 2022 – Jun 2022

Reviewer

International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS) International Conference on Advanced Robotics and Its Social Impacts (ARSO) Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L) International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

Skills

Programming Languages Python | C | C++ | Javascript | HTML | SQL | Matlab | LaTeX

Frameworks & Libraries OpenGL | OpenMP | Flask | Gym | PyTorch | Tensorflow | WandB

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT Git | Docker | CMake | VSCode | Jupyter

ROBOT DEVELOPMENT Motion Capture (OptiTrack) | ROS | MoveIt | OMPL

LANGUAGES English | Korean

Extra ____

AAMAS Student Volunteer

Student Venture Network, Seoul National University

College of Engineering Tennis Club, Seoul National University

Mar 2012 – July 2012

Mar 2010 – Feb 2013

System Administrator, ECE Department, Seoul National University

Mar 2010 – Feb 2011

SNU Mentoring, Seoul National University

Sep 2009 – Feb 2010